Finding Aid for Programs for Educational Opportunity (University of Michigan) records, 1969-2002
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Programs
  - Family Science Leadership Workshop 1992, 1994-2002, 6 folders (Box 21)
  - Middle School Family Math (Ypsilanti) (Pilot) 1995-1996 (Box 21)
  - Playtime is Science, Introduction to 2001-2002 [Session sponsored by Michigan Association for the Education of Young Children] (Box 21)
  - Playtime is Science Leadership Workshop 1994 (Box 21)
  - Playtime is Science Leadership Workshop and Reunion 1995 (Box 21)
  - Startling Statements 1994-2002 (Box 21)
- Reports
  Reports (.2 linear feet) is a small collection of reports produced by the PEO, including two evaluations of the Family Math program. There are also reports on the years 1997-2002, which were submitted by the PEO to the Michigan Department of Education as part of their annual application for the Eisenhower Higher Education Competitive Grant. The series is arranged alphabetically and spans the period 1981-2002, but most reports are from the years 1994-2002.
  - Annual Reports of Programs for Educational Opportunity and Center for Sex Equity in Schools 1981-1982 (Box 21)
  - Eisenhower Higher Education Competitive Grant Program 1997-2002, 2 folders (Box 21)
  - Families in Family Math Research Project, Final Report 1990 (Box 21)
  - Implementation of Family Math in Five Community Agencies 1988 (Box 21)
  - Playtime is Science, Educational Equity Concepts Evaluations 1994-1998 (Box 21)
- Center for Sex Equity in Schools
  The Center for Sex Equity in Schools (CSES) series (.5 linear feet) contains reports, manuals, correspondence, and minutes concerning that organization's programs and initiatives during the years 1980-2000. There are several documents about "Comparable Worth" studies, an effort to define a single, bias-free, job evaluation system which could be used to eliminate gender-defined wage gaps. The series also includes minutes from meetings of the District Network, a forum for school administrators in the Great Lakes region to discuss issues related to sex equity. Researchers who consult this series are advised to consult boxes 13 and 14, which contain earlier records of this organization.
  - Administration
    - Correspondence 1983-1986 (Box 22)
    - Presentations 1988 (Box 22)
    - Retreat (Ann Arbor) 1988 (Box 22)
  - Black English Symposium 1980 (Box 22)
  - Comparative Worth
    - Correspondence 1984-1985 (Box 22)
    - Mid-Atlantic Center for Sex Equity Presentation 1985 (Box 22)
    - Related Studies 1983-1984 (Box 22)
    - Simulation for the Training of School Personnel 1984 (Box 22)
    - What's It Worth? (Simulation for Training) 1985 (Box 22)
    - Zumbrota Public Schools Study, (Minnesota) 1985 (Box 22)
  - Arthur Coxford, Coreplus Development 1992 (Box 22)
  - District Network Meetings (1983-1987), 6 folders (Box 22)
  - EQTY:Net 1988-1989 (Box 22)
  - Fair Discipline Project 1983 (Box 22)
  - Forty Years of Struggle Toward Access and Equality 1995 [Town Hall Meeting, Ann Arbor, MI] (Box 22)
  - Gifted Children (articles and correspondence) 1983, 1994-1995 (Box 22)
  - Alice Kaseberg 2000 (Box 22)
  - "More Than Our Mother's Lot," 1989 [Tenth National Conference of National Coalition for Sex Equity in Education] (Box 22)
  - Public Education Programs for African-Americans 1983 (Box 22)
  - Public Education Programs for African-American Males 1991 (Box 22)
  - School Staff Evaluation 1986 [Applying Sex Equity Principles] (Box 22)
  - Women in School Administration 1990 (Box 22)
- Topical Files
  The Topical Files (.5 linear feet) contain correspondence, minutes, reports, and articles about equity and diversity from 1982 to 2002. The series includes materials from diversity workshops conducted by the University of Michigan's Information Technology Division and School of Education. There are also correspondence, minutes, and handouts from conferences about diversity, including Girls and Science and Technology (GASAT) and others concerning women in science. The series also documents workshops conducted for the Michigan Metro Girl Scout's Council and the Women's Initiative Group (WING).
  - Academic Women's Caucus, Climate for Women at University of Michigan 1985 (Box 22)
  - Academic Women's Caucus, Salary Equity Study Committee 1984 (Box 22)
  - American Educational Research Association, Research on Women and Education 1990 (Box 22)
  - Conferences on Equity 1991-1992 (Box 22)
  - Detroit Head Start 2000 (Box 22)
  - Girls and Science and Technology 1987 (Box 22)
  - Girls and Women in Conversation 1998 (Box 22)
  - Initial Entry into District undated (Box 22)
  - National Coalition for Sex Equity in Education 1993 (Box 22)
  - Diversity (Box 22)
  - Information Technology Division 1988-1990 (Box 22)
  - Information Technology Division, Facilitator Meeting 1990 (Box 22)
  - School of Education 1989-1990, 2002 (Box 22)
  - University Course 299 1992 (Box 22)
  - Marcia Federbush (writings) undated (Box 22)
  - Men Cooperating for a Change 1983 (Box 22)
  - Michigan Metro Girl Scouts Council 1991-1993 (Box 22)
  - Michigan Metro Girl Scout Council, Pluralism Workshop 1991 (Box 22)
  - Microsoft Proposals 2002 (Box 22)
  - Kate Myers, Correspondence (Box 22)
  - National Organization for Women, (Forgotten Corner) [Women who do not attend college] 1990 (Box 22)
  - National Science Foundation Regional Diversity 1996 (Box 22)
  - Regional Equity Networks 1989 (Box 22)
  - Regional Equity Network, Meeting 1989-1990 (Box 22)
  - "Revised Guide to Success," Contributions by Eleanor Linn 1996 (Box 22)
  - Women's Initiative Group (University of Michigan) 1987-1988 (Box 22)
  - Women's Initiative Group, Curriculum Task Force 1988-1991 (Box 22)
Related Material
Programs in Educational Opportunity (University of Michigan) records 1969-2002.
School of Education (University of Michigan) records 1904-ongoing.